<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blogs on Erik McClure</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Blogs on Erik McClure</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Erik McClure</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2022 18:44:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://erikmcclure.com/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>I'll Never Respect My Elders After What They've Done</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/never-respect-my-elders-after-what-they-did/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2022 18:44:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/never-respect-my-elders-after-what-they-did/</guid><description>21 years ago, I walked into my 5th grade teacher's classroom and it was dead silent. The TV was on. Something was happening that I didn't understand, but my instincts told me that This Was Very Wrong. That moment is carved into my memory not because of what actually happened on September 11th, which I was too young to fully grasp, but because the way the adults were behaving signaled to my young mind that this was very important and I needed to remember it.</description></item><item><title>Camp Vista - Growing Up Next To Microsoft</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/camp-vista/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2022 22:39:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/camp-vista/</guid><description>This blog was started on LiveJournal shortly after I graduated high school in 2009. It has survived this long because I was very persistent about porting all my posts to Blogger, and then to my own static website. Of course, I have limits. Most of my terrible old posts were removed long ago, because they were so bad they didn't contribute anything. One post was a rant about my high school internship at Microsoft.</description></item><item><title>Blockchain Is The New JavaScript</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/blockchain-new-javascript/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Oct 2021 01:06:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/blockchain-new-javascript/</guid><description>Over 25 years ago, Brenden Eich created JavaScript, named after Java simply because it was popular. It's prototypical nature and dynamic typing made it unsuitable for anything other than slow interpreters, forcing Google to invent a way to JIT the language just to make it fast. We even built a package manager for JavaScript which managed to create such an absurd dependency hell that one guy's left-pad function managed to break web development for a day.</description></item><item><title>C++ Constructors, Memory, and Lifetimes</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/cpp-constructors-memory-and-lifetimes/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2021 23:04:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/cpp-constructors-memory-and-lifetimes/</guid><description>What exactly happens when you write Foo* foo = new Foo();? A lot is packed into this one statement, so lets try to break it down. First, this example is allocating new memory on the heap, but in order to understand everything that's going on, we're going to have to explain what it means to declare a variable on the stack. If you already have a good understanding of how the stack works, and how functions do cleanup before returning, feel free to skip to the new statement.</description></item><item><title>Factorio Is The Best Technical Interview We Have</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/factorio-is-best-interview-we-have/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 15:26:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/factorio-is-best-interview-we-have/</guid><description>There's been a lot of hand-wringing over The Technical Interview lately. Many people realize that inverting a binary tree on a whiteboard has basically zero correlation to whether or not someone is actually a good software developer. The most effective programming test anyone's come up with is still Fizzbuzz. One consequence of this has been an increased emphasis on Open Source Contributions, but it turns out these aren't a very good metric either, because most people don't have that kind of time.</description></item><item><title>Why You Can't Use Prebuilt LLVM 10.0 with C++17</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/why-you-cant-use-prebuilt-llvm-with-cpp17/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2020 02:50:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/why-you-cant-use-prebuilt-llvm-with-cpp17/</guid><description>C++17 introduced an alignment argument to ::operator new(). It's important to note that if you allocate something using aligned new, you absolutely must deallocate it using aligned delete, or the behavior is undefined. LLVM 10.x takes advantage of this alignment parameter, if the compiler supports it. That means if you are compiling on Windows with MSVC set to C++14, __cpp_aligned_new is not defined and the extra argument isn't passed. Otherwise, if it's compiled with MSVC set to C++17, __cpp_aligned_new is defined and the extra argument is passed.</description></item><item><title>Someone Is Stealing Tracker Songs And Selling Them</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/someone-is-stealing-tracker-songs/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Mar 2020 12:08:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/someone-is-stealing-tracker-songs/</guid><description>Today, in response to a tweet talking about old untitled song ideas, I mentioned that I had a strange file called &amp;ldquo;t.mp3&amp;rdquo; sitting in my downloads folder that had been there for years and have no attached metadata or hint as to where it came from. It appeared to be a complete recording of a chiptune song, and it sounded very nice, but I had no way of knowing the original source.</description></item><item><title>Pressure Based Anti-Spam for Discord Bots</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/pressure-based-anti-spam-for-discord-bots/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2020 21:45:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/pressure-based-anti-spam-for-discord-bots/</guid><description>Back when Discord was a wee little chat platform with no rate limiting whatsoever, it's API had already been reverse-engineered by a bunch of bot developers who then went around spamming random servers with so many messages it would crash the client. My friends and I were determined to keep our discord server public, so I went about creating the first anti-spam bot for Discord.
I am no longer maintaining this bot beyond simple bugfixes because I have better things to do with my time, and I'm tired of people trying to use it because &amp;ldquo;it's the best anti-spam bot&amp;rdquo; even after I deprecated it.</description></item><item><title>Name Shadowing Should Be An Operator</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/name-shadowing-should-be-an-operator/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2019 13:23:58 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/name-shadowing-should-be-an-operator/</guid><description>I recently discovered that in Rust, this is a relatively common operation: let foo = String::from(&amp;#34;foo&amp;#34;); // stuff that needs ownership let foo = &amp;amp;foo; Or this: let mut vec = Vec::new(); vec.push(&amp;#34;a&amp;#34;); vec.push(&amp;#34;b&amp;#34;); let vec = vec; /* vec is immutable now */ This is a particularly permissive form of name-shadowing, which allows you to re-declare a variable in an inner scope that shadows the name of a variable in an outer scope, making the outer variable inaccessible.</description></item><item><title>A Rant On Terra</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/a-rant-on-terra/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2019 17:08:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/a-rant-on-terra/</guid><description>Metaprogramming, or the ability to inspect, modify and generate code at compile-time (as opposed to reflection, which is runtime introspection of code), has slowly been gaining momentum. Programmers are finally admitting that, after accidentally inventing turing complete template systems, maybe we should just have proper first-class support for generating code. Rust has macros, Zig has built-in compile time expressions, Nim lets you rewrite the AST however you please, and dependent types have been cropping up all over the place.</description></item><item><title>RISC Is Fundamentally Unscalable</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/risc-is-fundamentally-unscalable/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2019 20:09:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/risc-is-fundamentally-unscalable/</guid><description>Today, there was an announcement about a new RISC-V chip, which has got a lot of people excited. I wish I could also be excited, but to me, this is just a reminder that RISC architectures are fundamentally unscalable, and inevitably stop being RISC as soon as they need to be fast. People still call ARM a &amp;ldquo;RISC&amp;rdquo; architecture despite ARMv8.3-A adding a FJCVTZS instruction, which is &amp;ldquo;Floating-point Javascript Convert to Signed fixed-point, rounding toward Zero&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>Software Engineering Is Bad, But That's Not Why</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/software-engineering-is-bad-but-it-s-not-that-bad/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 11:03:49 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/software-engineering-is-bad-but-it-s-not-that-bad/</guid><description>I've been writing code for over 12 years, and for a while I've been disgusted by the sorry state of programming. That's why I felt a deep kinship with Nikita Prokopov's article, Software Disenchantment. It captures the intense feeling of frustration I have with the software industry as a whole and the inability of modern programmers to write anything even remotely resembling efficient systems.
Unfortunately, much of it is wrong.</description></item><item><title>Why Do People Use The Wrong Email?</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/why-do-people-use-the-wrong-email-/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jul 2018 10:57:26 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/why-do-people-use-the-wrong-email-/</guid><description>Ever since 2013, I've consistently started getting registration e-mails in foreign languages from sites I definitely did not sign up for.
It started with Instagram, on which a bizarrely determined young boy from somewhere around Denmark was trying to register using my e-mail address. Instagram lets you remove an e-mail from an account, which is what I did, repeatedly, but the kid kept adding the non-functional e-mail back on to the account.</description></item><item><title>Software Optimizes to Single Points of Failure</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/software-optimizes-to-single-points-of-failure/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2018 18:01:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/software-optimizes-to-single-points-of-failure/</guid><description>Whenever people talk about removing single points of failure, most of the suggestions involve &amp;ldquo;distributed systems&amp;rdquo; that are resilient to hardware failures. For software, we've invented code signing and smart contracts via blockchain to ensure the code we're running is what we expected to run.
But none of these technologies can prevent a bug from taking down the entire system.
A lot of people point to Google being a single point of failure.</description></item><item><title>Migrating To A Static Blog</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/migrating-to-static-blog/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2018 09:07:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/migrating-to-static-blog/</guid><description>I've finished constructing a new personal website for myself using hugo, and I'm moving my blog over there so I have more control over what gets loaded, and more importantly, so the page doesn't attempt to load Blogger's 5 MB worth of bloated javascript nonsense just to read some text. It also fixes math and code highlighting while reading on mobile. If you reached this post using Blogger, you'll be redirected or will soon be redirected to the corresponding post on my new website.</description></item><item><title>How To Avoid Memorizing Times Tables</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/how-to-avoid-memorizing-times-tables/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 11:37:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/how-to-avoid-memorizing-times-tables/</guid><description>I was recently told that my niece was trying to memorize her times tables. As an applied mathematician whose coding involves plenty of multiplication, I was not happy to hear this. Nobody who does math actually memorizes times tables, and furthermore, forcing a child to memorize anything is probably the worst possible thing you can do in modern society. No one should memorize their times tables, they should learn how to calculate them.</description></item><item><title>Ignoring Outliers Creates Racist Algorithms</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/ignoring-outliers-creates-racist/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 15:26:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/ignoring-outliers-creates-racist/</guid><description>Have you built an algorithm that mostly works? Does it account for almost everyone's needs, save for a few weird outliers that you ignore because they make up 0.0001% of the population? Congratulations, your algorithm is racist! To illustrate how this happens, let's take a recent example from Facebook. My friend's message was removed for &amp;ldquo;violating community standards&amp;rdquo;. Now, my friend has had all sorts of ridiculous problems with Facebook, so to test my theory, I posted the exact same message on my page, and then had him report it.</description></item><item><title>I Used To Want To Work For Google</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/i-used-to-want-to-work-for-google/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2017 01:04:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/i-used-to-want-to-work-for-google/</guid><description>A long time ago I thought Google was this magical company that truly cared about engineering and solving problems instead of maximizing shareholder value. Then Larry Page became CEO and I realized they were not a magical unicorn and lamented the fact that they had been transformed into &amp;ldquo;just another large company&amp;rdquo;. Several important things happened between that post and now: Microsoft got a new CEO, so I decided to give them a shot and got hired there.</description></item><item><title>Sexist Programmers Are Awful Engineers</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/sexist-programmers-are-awful-engineers/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2017 12:20:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/sexist-programmers-are-awful-engineers/</guid><description>Men and women are fundamentally different. So are white people and black people and autistic people and gay people and transgender people and conservatives and liberals and every other human being along every imaginable axis of discrimination. Some of these differences are cultural. Others are genetic. Others depend on environmental factors. These differences mean that some of us are inherently better at certain tasks than others. On average, men are better at spatial temporal reasoning, women are better at reading comprehension and writing ability, and psychopaths can sometimes be excellent CEOs.</description></item><item><title>Why I Never Built My SoundCloud Killer</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/why-i-never-built-my-soundcloud-killer/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2017 16:57:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/why-i-never-built-my-soundcloud-killer/</guid><description>While the news of SoundCloud imploding are fairly recent, musicians and producers have had a beef with the music uploading site's direction for years. I still remember when SoundCloud only gave you a paltry 2 hours worth of free upload time and managed to convert my high quality lossless WAV files to the shittiest 128 kbps MP3 I've ever heard in my life. What really pissed me off was that they demanded a ridiculous $7 a month just to double your upload time.</description></item><item><title>Integrating LuaJIT and Autogenerating C Bindings In Visual Studio</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/integrating-luajit-and-autogenerating-c/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2017 23:15:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/integrating-luajit-and-autogenerating-c/</guid><description>Lua is a popular scripting language due to its tight integration with C. LuaJIT is an extremely fast JIT compiler for Lua that can be integrated into your game, which also provides an FFI Library that directly interfaces with C functions, eliminating most overhead. However, the FFI library only accepts a subset of the C standard. Specifically, &amp;ldquo;C declarations are not passed through a C pre-processor, yet. No pre-processor tokens are allowed, except for #pragma pack.</description></item><item><title>Discord: Rise Of The Bot Wars</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/discord-rise-of-bot-wars/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jun 2017 08:40:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/discord-rise-of-bot-wars/</guid><description>The most surreal experience I ever had on discord was when someone PMed me to complain that my anti-spam bot wasn't working against a 200+ bot raid. I pointed out that it was never designed for large-scale attacks, and that discord's own rate-limiting would likely make it useless. He revealed he was selling spambot accounts at a rate of about $1 for 100 unique accounts and that he was being attacked by a rival spammer.</description></item><item><title>Programmers Should Take Linguistics</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/programmers-should-take-linguistics/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 15:48:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/programmers-should-take-linguistics/</guid><description>The older I get, the more I realize that 90% of all disagreements or social drama results from a miscommunication of some kind. Every time I wind up having to resolve a dispute, I'll try to get both sides of the story, only to realize that they're the same story, and both parties were actually either in agreement or fighting over a perceived insult that never actually existed. Unsurprisingly, a disproportionate amount of this miscommunication often involves programmers being far too strict with their interpretations of what certain words mean.</description></item><item><title>Companies Can't Be Apolitical</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/companies-cant-be-apolitical/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2017 00:37:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/companies-cant-be-apolitical/</guid><description>One of the most common things I hear from people is that companies should be &amp;ldquo;apolitical&amp;rdquo;. The most formal way this concept is expressed is that a company should make decisions based on what maximizes profits and not political opinions. Unfortunately, the statement &amp;ldquo;companies should only care about maximizing profits&amp;rdquo; is, itself, a political statement (and one I happen to disagree with). Thus, it is fundamentally impossible for a company to be truly apolitical, for the very act of attempting to be apolitical is a political statement.</description></item><item><title>I Can't Hear Anything Below 80 Hz*</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/i-cant-hear-anything-below-80-hz/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2017 15:06:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/i-cant-hear-anything-below-80-hz/</guid><description>EDIT: I have confirmed all the results presented here by taking the low frequency test with someone standing physically next to me. They heard a tone beginning at 30 Hz, and by the time I could hear a very faint tone around 70 Hz, they described the tone as &amp;ldquo;conversation volume level&amp;rdquo;, which is about 60 dB. I did not reach this perceived volume level until about 120 Hz, which strongly correlates with the experiment.</description></item><item><title>Windows Won't Let My Program Crash</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/windows-wont-let-my-program-crash/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2017 21:33:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/windows-wont-let-my-program-crash/</guid><description>It's been known for a while that windows has a bad habit of eating your exceptions if you're inside a WinProc callback function. This behavior can cause all sorts of mayhem, like your program just vanishing into thin air without any error messages due to a stack overflow that terminated the program without actually throwing an exception. What I didn't realize is that it also eats assert(), which makes debugging hell, because the assertion would throw, the entire user callback would immediately terminate without any stack unwinding, and then windows would just&amp;hellip; keep going, even though the program is now in a laughably corrupt state, because only half the function executed.</description></item><item><title>DirectX Is Terrifying</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/directx-is-terrifying/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 19:35:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/directx-is-terrifying/</guid><description>About two months ago, I got a new laptop and proceeded to load all my projects on it. Despite compiling everything fine, my graphics engine that used DirectX mysteriously crashed upon running. I immediately suspected either a configuration issue or a driver issue, but this seemed weird because my laptop had a newer graphics card than my desktop. Why was it crashing on newer hardware? Things got even more bizarre once I narrowed down the issue - it was in my shader assignment code, which hadn't been touched in almost 2 years.</description></item><item><title>Our Software Is a Beacon of Hope</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/our-software-is-beacon-of-hope/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2017 14:35:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/our-software-is-beacon-of-hope/</guid><description>As I draw closer to releasing the first early alpha of a library I've been working on for several years, I've noticed that it's release time coincides with some rather depressing politics that I wish I could ignore. Unfortunately, it's difficult to ignore politicians who seek to destroy the lives of your closest friends. A common theme I hear from my friends is a feeling of helplessness, as though we all know terrible things are happening, but no one really knows what to do about it.</description></item><item><title>Everyone Does sRGB Wrong Because Everyone Else Does sRGB Wrong</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/everyone-does-srgb-wrong-because/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2016 15:26:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/everyone-does-srgb-wrong-because/</guid><description>Did you know that CSS3 does all its linear gradients and color interpolation completely wrong? All color values in CSS3 are in the sRGB color space, because that's the color space that gets displayed on our monitor. However, the problem is that the sRGB color space looks like this:
Trying to do a linear interpolation along a nonlinear curve doesn't work very well. Instead, you're supposed to linearize your color values, transforming the sRGB curve to the linear RGB curve before doing your operation, and then transforming it back into the sRGB curve.</description></item><item><title>Mathematical Notation Is Awful</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/mathematical-notation-is-awful/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jul 2016 22:18:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/mathematical-notation-is-awful/</guid><description>Today, a friend asked me for help figuring out how to calculate the standard deviation over a discrete probability distribution. I pulled up my notes from college and was able to correctly calculate the standard deviation they had been unable to derive after hours upon hours of searching the internet and trying to piece together poor explanations from questionable sources. The crux of the problem was, as I had suspected, the astonishingly bad notation involved with this particular calculation.</description></item><item><title>The GPL Is Usually Overkill</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/the-gpl-is-usually-overkill/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2016 14:23:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/the-gpl-is-usually-overkill/</guid><description>Something that really bothers me about the GPL and free software crusaders in general is that they don't seem to understand the nuances behind the problem they are attempting to solve. I'm not entirely sure they are even trying to solve the right problem in the first place.
The core issue at play here is control. In a world run by software, we need control over what code is being executed on our hardware.</description></item><item><title>The Right To Ignore: The Difference Between Free Speech And Harassment</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/the-right-to-ignore-difference-between/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2016 21:27:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/the-right-to-ignore-difference-between/</guid><description>On one hand, America was built on the values of free speech, which are obviously important. We cannot control what people are saying or our democracy falls apart. On the other hand, allowing harassment has a stifling effect on free speech, because it allows people to be bullied into silence. Before the internet, this distinction was fairly simple: Someone with a megaphone screaming hate speech in a park is exercising their right to free speech.</description></item><item><title>There Will Never Be One True Programming Language</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/there-will-never-be-one-true/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2015 03:07:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/there-will-never-be-one-true/</guid><description>A disturbing number of otherwise intelligent programmers seem to believe that, one day in the distant future, everyone will use the same magical programming language that solves everyone's problems at the same time. Often, this involves garbage collection, with lots of hand-waving about computers built with Applied Phlebotinum.
For the sake of argument, let's assume it is the year 30XX, and we are a budding software developer on Mars. We have quantum computers that run on magic pixie dust and let us calculate almost anything we want as fast as we want so long as we don't break any laws of physics.</description></item><item><title>Abortion Has No Moral High Ground</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/abortion-has-no-moral-high-ground/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2015 01:55:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/abortion-has-no-moral-high-ground/</guid><description>June 26, 2015 was a historic moment. That was the day the Supreme Court legalized gay marriage on a federal level in the United States. As far as I'm concerned, this victory was the inevitable result of a point of view that relied entirely on logical fallacies and irrational hatred. Yet, it was a battle that was fought for centuries, and continues on, as obstinate conservatives vow to continue fighting to the bitter end.</description></item><item><title>I Tried To Install Linux And Now I Regret Everything</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/i-tried-to-install-linux-and-now-i/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2015 00:45:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/i-tried-to-install-linux-and-now-i/</guid><description>This story began with me getting pissed off at Windows for reasons that don't really need to be articulated. Just, pick your favorite reason to hate Windows, and let's pretend that was the tipping point. I had some spare space on my secondary drive, so I decided to give Linux another whirl. After all, it had been three or four years since I last attempted anything like this (it's been so long I don't rightly remember the last time I tried), and people have been saying that Linux has gotten a lot better recently!</description></item><item><title>We Aren't Designing Software For Robots</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/you-arent-designing-software-for-robots/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2015 01:13:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/you-arent-designing-software-for-robots/</guid><description>For some reason, many programmers seem to struggle with the concept of people being different. They get hung up on this naïve concept of right or wrong, as if life is some kind of mathematical equation that has a closed form solution. Let me say right now that any solution to life is going to be one heck of a chaotic nonlinear PDE, which won't have any closed form solution at all, and certainly not one using elementary functions.</description></item><item><title>Using Data To Balance Your Game: Pony Clicker Analysis</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/using-data-to-balance-your-game-pony/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2015 10:36:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/using-data-to-balance-your-game-pony/</guid><description>Incrementer and idle games are seemingly simplistic games where you wait or click to increase a counter, then use that counter to buy things to make the counter go up faster. Because of the compounding effects involved, these types of games inevitably turn into a study of growth rates and how different functions interact. Cookie Clicker is perhaps the most well-known, which employs an exponential growth curve for the costs of buildings that looks like this:</description></item><item><title>Is There A Commercial Open Source License?</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/is-there-commercial-open-source-license/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2015 03:25:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/is-there-commercial-open-source-license/</guid><description>Putting Commercial and Open-Source together is often considered an oxymoron. Part of this is caused by constant confusion between the terms Open-Source and Free Software, which is made even worse by people who have more liberal interpretations of the phrase &amp;ldquo;Open-Source&amp;rdquo;. In many cases, keeping the source code of a product proprietary serves no other purpose than to prevent people from stealing the product. Putting an application under the GPL and selling it is perfectly reasonable for software aimed at end-users, whom are unlikely to know how to compile the freely available source.</description></item><item><title>Does Anyone Actually Want Good Software?</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/does-anyone-actually-want-good-software/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2015 23:10:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/does-anyone-actually-want-good-software/</guid><description>Are there any programmers left that actually care about writing good software? As far as I can tell, the software development industry has turned into a series of echo chambers where managers scream about new features and shipping software and analyzing feedback from customers. Then they ignore all the feedback and implement whatever new things are supposed to be cool, like flat design, or cloud computing, or software as a service.</description></item><item><title>Why Don't You Just Fire Them?</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/why-dont-you-just-fire-them/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2015 01:32:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/why-dont-you-just-fire-them/</guid><description>Programmers love to bash things like templates and multiple-inheritance and operator overloading, saying that they are abused too often and must be unilaterally banned, going so far as to design them out of their programming languages thinking this is somehow going to save them.
This makes about as much sense as saying that bank robbers use cars to escape police too much, so we need to ban cars.
Templates, fundamentally, are very useful and perfectly reasonable things to use in most sane contexts.</description></item><item><title>How Not To Install Software</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/how-not-to-sell-software/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2014 18:53:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/how-not-to-sell-software/</guid><description>It's that time of the year again, when everyone and their pony puts on a sale, except now it seems to have started much earlier than the traditional Black Friday. Needless to say, this is the only time of year I go around buying expensive sample libraries. One of these libraries was recommended by a friend: LA Scoring Strings - First Chair 2, a cheaper version of LA Scoring Strings. It's $100 off, which is pretty nice, except that the page that describes the product doesn't actually have a link to buy it.</description></item><item><title>Never Reinventing The Wheel Is Anticompetitive</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/not-reinventing-wheel-is-anticompetitive/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2014 00:15:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/not-reinventing-wheel-is-anticompetitive/</guid><description>Nowadays, you aren't supposed to write anything yourself. In the world of open-source software, you're supposed to find a library that does what you want, and if that doesn't work, commit a change that makes it work. Writing your own library is a bad thing because it's perceived as redundant if there's already a library that does most of what you want. The problem is that this is inherently anti-competitive. If there's only one library that does something, you have a monopoly, and then you get Heartbleed, because there's zero diversification.</description></item><item><title>Everyone Can Be Above Average</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/everyone-can-be-above-average/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2014 01:13:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/everyone-can-be-above-average/</guid><description>Time and time again, I hear the wise old members of our society insisting that my generation has been gravely misled. They claim that, by telling every child that they are special, no one is. They claim that everyone can't be above average.
This is painfully ridiculous.
When someone says that every child is special, they are saying that each child is special in their own way. Each child is blessed with a gift of their own, wholly unique to them.</description></item><item><title>Can We Choose What We Enjoy?</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/can-we-choose-what-we-enjoy/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2014 13:14:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/can-we-choose-what-we-enjoy/</guid><description>One of the most bizarre arguments I have ever heard in ethics is whether or not people can choose to be gay or not. The idea is, if being gay is genetically predetermined, it's not their fault, therefore you can't prosecute them for something they have no control over.
Since when did anyone get to choose what makes them happy? Can you choose to like strawberries? Can you choose to enjoy the smell of dandelions?</description></item><item><title>How To Make Your Profiler 10x Faster</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/how-to-make-your-profiler-10x-faster/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Jun 2014 17:31:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/how-to-make-your-profiler-10x-faster/</guid><description>Frustrated with C profilers that are either so minimal as to be useless, or giant behemoths that require you to install device drivers, I started writing a lightweight profiler for my utility library. I already had a high precision timer class, so it was just a matter of using a radix trie that didn't blow up the cache. I was very careful about minimizing the impact the profiler had on the code, even going so far as to check if extended precision floating point calculations were slowing it down.</description></item><item><title>The Problem With Photorealism</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/the-problem-with-photorealism/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2014 09:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/the-problem-with-photorealism/</guid><description>Many people assume that modern graphics technology is now capable of rendering photorealistic video games. If you define photorealistic as any still frame is indistinguishable from a real photo, then we can get pretty close. Unfortunately, the problem with video games is that they are not still frames - they move.
What people don't realize is that modern games rely on faking a lot of stuff, and that means they only look photorealistic in a very tight set of circumstances.</description></item><item><title>Success Is Relative</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/success-is-relative/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2014 16:32:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/success-is-relative/</guid><description>It seems that many people view success as some sort of absolute value, usually inextricably tied to how much money you make. Ignoring the fact that we should not be tying success to monetary value, we should also not be treating success as some sort of absolute value based on where you end up. What really matters is where you started from.
Climbing a mountain is not that impressive when you start half a mile from the peak.</description></item><item><title>Google's Decline Really Bugs Me</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/googles-decline-really-bugs-me/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2013 11:13:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/googles-decline-really-bugs-me/</guid><description>Google is going down the drain.
That isn't to say they aren't fantastically successful. They are. I still use their products, mostly because I don't put things on the internet I don't want other people to find, and I'm not female, so I don't have to worry about misogynists stalking me. They still make stupendous amounts of money and pump out some genuinely good software. They still have the best search engine.</description></item><item><title>The Educational Imbroglio</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/the-educational-imbroglio/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2013 19:58:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/the-educational-imbroglio/</guid><description>The most recent and perhaps egregious example of this is a breathtakingly misguided article by Kevin G. Welner, who is the director of the National Education Policy center, which is absolutely terrifying. He is attempting to discredit the idea of &amp;ldquo;tracking&amp;rdquo;, wherein low-performing students are separated from higher achieving students, because obviously you can't teach kids who &amp;ldquo;get it&amp;rdquo; the same way as kids who are struggling. Unfortunately, the entire conclusion rests on a logical fallacy.</description></item><item><title>The Ladder-Climbing Generation</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/the-ladder-climbing-generation/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2013 15:10:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/the-ladder-climbing-generation/</guid><description>To invent your own life's meaning is not easy, but it's still allowed, and I think you'll be happier for the trouble.*
 — Bill Watterson, 1990 speech at Kenyon CollegeSomeone, once again, is complaining about those misbehaving youngsters who don't understand the value of hard work. He lampoons the advice to follow your passion, saying that young people are just scared of hard work. He makes the dangerously misinformed claim that burn-out is just a myth: &amp;ldquo;Burn out is just a rationalization for giving up early.</description></item><item><title>The Microsoft Word Problem</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/the-microsoft-word-problem/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2013 22:34:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/the-microsoft-word-problem/</guid><description>I use FL Studio 11 to make my music. Some people find this surprising, due to FL Studio's stigma as being a &amp;ldquo;toy&amp;rdquo; DAW that it simply cannot seem to shake, despite the fact it actually does most things as well or better than other professional DAWs. FL Studio has two real, significant issues: Large projects are unstable, and it has extremely bad 64-bit support.
This is almost never what people actually complain about.</description></item><item><title>Write Less Code</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/write-less-code/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2013 10:36:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/write-less-code/</guid><description>The burgeoning complexity of software is perhaps one of the most persistent problems plaguing computer science. We have tried many, many ways of managing this complexity: inventing new languages, creating management systems, and enforcing coding styles. They have all proven to be nothing more than stopgaps. With the revelation that the NSA is utilizing the inherent complexity of software systems to sabotage our efforts at securing our systems, this problem has become even more urgent.</description></item><item><title>Most People Have Shitty Computers</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/most-people-have-shitty-computers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2013 21:29:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/most-people-have-shitty-computers/</guid><description>Ever since I started putting words on the internet, I have complained about the misinterpretation and overgeneralization of this Donald Knuth quote. Developers essentially use it as an excuse to never optimize anything, because they can always say they &amp;ldquo;aren't done yet&amp;rdquo; and then permanently render all optimizations as premature. The fact that &amp;ldquo;premature&amp;rdquo; is inherently a subjective term doesn't help. The quote was meant to target very low-level optimizations that are largely useless until you're positive everything else is working properly and you have no other low-hanging fruit to optimize.</description></item><item><title>Leap Motion Impressions, Input Sanitation, and 3D Gesture Ideas</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/leap-motion-impressions-input/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2013 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/leap-motion-impressions-input/</guid><description>For the most part, does what it claims it does, and gives you extremely precise, fast tracking of fingers. Cons:
Really hates thumbs for some reason. Has a lot of trouble with pens or other implements. Fingers must be separated. Fairly easy to get positions that break the camera because it can't see the fingers. *No one has any idea how to write software for it.* I just got my Leap Motion device today, and for the most part, I like it.</description></item><item><title>Aurora Theory Released!</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/aurora-theory-released/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2013 19:27:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/aurora-theory-released/</guid><description>Aurora Theory has been released! Buy it on bandcamp for $9, or $10 on iTunes, Amazon, and Google Play. The album is also available on Spotify, last.fm, other online radios, and can be previewed on YouTube.
Aurora Theory has been 4 years in the making, a compilation of all the songs I managed to make in the middle of attending university. The earlier songs have been extensively improved, and all songs have been remastered for the album's release.</description></item><item><title>What I Learned In College</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/what-i-learned-in-college/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2013 07:56:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/what-i-learned-in-college/</guid><description>Yesterday, the University of Washington finally mailed me my diploma. A Bachelor of Science in Applied Computational Math and Science: Discrete Math and Algorithms. I learned a lot of things in college. I learned how to take tests and how to pinpoint exactly what useless crap a particular final needed me to memorize. I learned that math is an incredibly beautiful thing that has been butchered so badly I hated it all the way until my second year of college.</description></item><item><title>How To Complain About Men And Be Sexist At The Same Time</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/how-to-complain-about-men-and-be-sexist/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2013 16:54:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/how-to-complain-about-men-and-be-sexist/</guid><description>What if I told you about an article that complained about how social media and instant gratification has eroded away at our social fabric? How we don't take the time to pause and reflect on how we live our lives? How we fail to really work at making the world a better place, and instead waste time building websites to share cat photos on? I'd think that it raised several important issues about modern society.</description></item><item><title>Course Notes</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/course-notes/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2013 18:39:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/course-notes/</guid><description>It's standard procedure at the University of Washington to allow a single sheet of handwritten notes during a Mathematics exam. I started collecting these sheets after I realized how useful it was to have a reference that basically summarized all the useful parts of the course on a single sheet of paper. Now that I've graduated, it's easy for me to quickly forget all the things I'm not using. The problem is that, when I need to say, develop an algorithm for simulating turbulent airflow, I need to go back and re-learn vector calculus, differential equations and nonlinear dynamics.</description></item><item><title>Contact</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/contact/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2013 04:46:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/contact/</guid><description>Many people assume the message behind Contact is that Religion and Science aren't mutually exclusive, but this is only part of the equation. Contact is really about faith. It's about never losing faith in your own passion, regardless of what it is. It can be science, religion, art, music, it doesn't matter. All that matters is that you find your passion, and you have faith in it, and no matter what happens, no matter what stands in your way, you fight for it.</description></item><item><title>The Dark Side of Web Development</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/the-dark-side-of-htmlcss/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Feb 2013 20:54:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/the-dark-side-of-htmlcss/</guid><description>I am, by no means, a very good web developer. I am, however, a highly experienced C++ developer. The end result is that people usually ask me why I like C++ so much when everyone else hates it, and everyone is supposedly in agreement that C++ is the worst language ever made and unless you are writing drivers you should never, ever use it. I mean, you can write games in Python now, right?</description></item><item><title>Windows Breaks assert() Inside WM_CANCELMODE</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/windows-breaks-assert-inside/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2013 20:17:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/windows-breaks-assert-inside/</guid><description>So I have this dll that's doing a bunch of horrible WinAPI calls for me. It's designed to abstract away all the pain and unholy functions feeding on innocent blood. Little did I know that trying to cage WinAPI into a more manageable corner would be my undoing.
The window is created and assigned a WndProc callback function inside this DLL, as per the various absurd requirements involving how you create windows in Windows.</description></item><item><title>Dreams Are Worth Fighting For</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/dreams-are-worth-fighting-for/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2013 16:20:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/dreams-are-worth-fighting-for/</guid><description>While I have never been suicidal, I've had to deal with suicidal friends more than I'd like. The hardest thing in the world is to get suicidal people to understand that, contrary to their entire life's experience, and contrary to every shred of evidence they have, things will get better. Eventually, they will have an experience they could never have imagined, they just have to hold on long enough. Sometimes it feels like our dreams are on the brink of suicide for similar reasons, and we must also convince ourselves that we just need to hold on to them for a little while longer.</description></item><item><title>The Productivity Fallacy</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/the-productivity-fallacy/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jan 2013 17:12:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/the-productivity-fallacy/</guid><description>Technology tends to serve one of two purposes - to make us more efficient at some task, or to entertain us in our resulting free time. However, when we fixate on productivity to the exclusion of everything else, we often forget about the big picture. Perhaps the best example of this are people insisting that real coders need to use Vim to be productive due to it's unmatched text editing powers.</description></item><item><title>The Earbud Loudness Wars</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/the-earbud-loudness-wars/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Jan 2013 19:15:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/the-earbud-loudness-wars/</guid><description>I have a Zune I got as a prize at a Microsoft Hunt The Wumpus competition back when Microsoft was still under the delusion that they could actually compete with the iPod. My Zune has served me faithfully for almost 7 years. I am now on my third pair of earbuds for my Zune, and have noticed a disturbing trend.
The Zune has a volume control that goes from 0 to 20.</description></item><item><title>Giant List of FREE SAMPLES</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/giant-list-of-free-samples/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Dec 2012 19:49:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/giant-list-of-free-samples/</guid><description>Back when I started making music, I quickly realized that trying to make sample-based music without a significant sample library is really hard. While there are thousands of sample libraries for sale, the problem with starting out is that, by definition, you suck, you're probably in high school, and your allowance is likely going towards other, more important things, and not your silly musical experiments.
Over the years, I've been frustrated with how difficult it is to find good free samples.</description></item><item><title>The Weekend I Got Lost All The Time</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/the-weekend-apelsin-got-lost-all-time/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2012 23:24:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/the-weekend-apelsin-got-lost-all-time/</guid><description>So on thursday morning my friend mentioned a hackathon at his college, San Jose University. I expressed interest but pointed out that I live 800 miles away. So he bought me a ticket on the last plane flying to San Francisco that night. 10 hours after he had mentioned this hackathon with me, I was riding on a train to San Jose University (after missing one train and getting off on the wrong stop).</description></item><item><title>C# to C++ Tutorial - Part 4: Operator Overload</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/c-to-c-tutorial-part-4-operator-overload/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Oct 2012 11:16:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/c-to-c-tutorial-part-4-operator-overload/</guid><description>[ 1 · 2 · 3 · 4 · 5 · 6 · 7]
If you are familiar with C#, you should be familiar with the difference between C#&amp;lsquo;s struct and class declarations. Namely, a struct is a value type and a class is a reference type, meaning that if you pass a struct to a function, its default behavior is for the entire struct to be copied into the function's parameter, so any modifications made to it won't affect whatever was passed in.</description></item><item><title>7 Problems Raytracing Doesn't Solve</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/7-problems-raytracing-doesnt-solve/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2012 04:13:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/7-problems-raytracing-doesnt-solve/</guid><description>I see a lot of people get excited about extreme concurrency in modern hardware bringing us closer to the magical holy grail of raytracing. It seems that everyone thinks that once we have raytracing, we can fully simulate entire digital worlds, everything will be photorealistic, and graphics will become a &amp;ldquo;solved problem&amp;rdquo;. This simply isn't true, and in fact highlights several fundamental misconceptions about the problems faced by modern games and other interactive media.</description></item><item><title>Teenage Rebellion as a Failure of Society</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/teenage-rebellion-as-failure-of-society/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Sep 2012 20:37:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/teenage-rebellion-as-failure-of-society/</guid><description>Historians have noticed that the concept of teenage rebellion is a modern invention. Young adults often (but not always) have a tendency to be horny and impulsive, but the flagrant and sometimes violent rejection of authority associated with teenagers is a stereotype unique to modern culture. Many adults incorrectly assume this means we have gotten &amp;ldquo;too soft&amp;rdquo; and need to bring back spanking, paddles, and other harsher methods of punishment. As any respectable young adult will tell you, that isn't the answer, and in fact highlights the underlying issue of ageism that is creating an aloof, frustrated, and repressed youth.</description></item><item><title>Analyzing XKCD: Click and Drag</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/analyzing-xkcd-click-and-drag/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2012 07:33:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/analyzing-xkcd-click-and-drag/</guid><description>Today, xkcd featured a comic with a comically large image that is navigated by clicking and dragging. In the interests of SCIENCE (and possibly accidentally DDoSing Randall's image server - sorry!), I created a static HTML file of the entire composite image.1
The collage is made up of 225 images2 that stretch out over a total image area 79872 pixels high and 165888 pixels wide. The images take up 5.52 MB of space and are named with a simple naming scheme &amp;#34;ydxd.</description></item><item><title>What Is A Right Answer?</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/what-is-right-answer/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2012 18:40:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/what-is-right-answer/</guid><description>I find that modern culture is often obsessed with a concept of wrongness. It is a tendency to paint things in a black and white fashion, as if there are simply wrong answers and right answers and nothing in-between. While I have seen this in every single imaginable discipline (including art and music, which is particularly disturbing), it is most obvious to me in the realm of programming.
When people aren't making astonishingly over-generalized statements like trying to say one programming language is better than another without context, we often try to find the &amp;ldquo;best&amp;rdquo; way to do something.</description></item><item><title>Coordinate Systems And Cascading Stupidity</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/coordinate-systems-and-cascading/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jul 2012 01:06:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/coordinate-systems-and-cascading/</guid><description>Today I learned that there are way too many coordinate systems, and that I'm an idiot (but that was already well-established). I have also learned to not trust graphics tutorials, but the reasons for that won't become apparent until the end of this article.
There are two types of coordinate systems: left-handed and right-handed coordinate systems. By convention, most everyone in math and science uses right-handed coordinate systems with positive x going to the right, positive y going up, and positive z coming out of the screen.</description></item><item><title>How Joysticks Ruined My Graphics Engine</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/how-joysticks-ruined-my-graphics-engine/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Jun 2012 22:29:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/how-joysticks-ruined-my-graphics-engine/</guid><description>It's almost a tradition.
Every time my graphics engine has been stuck in maintenence mode for 6 months, I'll suddenly realize I need to push out an update or implement some new feature. I then realize that I haven't actually paid attention to any of my testing programs, or their speed, in months. This is followed by panic, as I discover my engine running at half speed, or worse. Having made an infinite number of tiny tweaks that all could have caused the problem, I am often thrown into temporary despair only to almost immediately find some incredibly stupid mistake that was causing it.</description></item><item><title>Properly Dreaming About Success</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/properly-dreaming-about-success/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 May 2012 05:56:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/properly-dreaming-about-success/</guid><description>The wisdom of antiquity suggests that we must first imagine what we want to achieve if we are ever to succeed, but science has other ideas. A study demonstrated that visualizing yourself reaching a goal tricks your brain into thinking you actually did it, causing a relaxation response, which in turn robs you of ambition and energy.
This is a troubling counter-argument to age-old wisdom, but perhaps both sides can be right?</description></item><item><title>Multithreading Problems In Game Design</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/multithreading-problems-in-game-design/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2012 23:46:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/multithreading-problems-in-game-design/</guid><description>A couple years ago, when I first started designing a game engine to unify Box2D and my graphics engine, I thought this was a superb opportunity to join all the cool kids and multithread it. I mean all the other game developers were talking about having a thread for graphics, a thread for physics, a thread for audio, etc. etc. etc. So I spent a lot of time teaching myself various lockless threading techniques and building quite a few iterations of various multithreading structures.</description></item><item><title>IP Law Makes You an Asshole</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/ip-law-makes-you-asshole/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2012 15:27:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/ip-law-makes-you-asshole/</guid><description>I haven't had a very good relationship with IP law. My 2 favorite childhood game franchises - Descent and Freespace, were thrown into IP limbo after Interplay shot itself in the foot too many times and finally fell over. As a result, I have come to utterly despise the common practice of publishers simply taking the IP of the developers for themselves, and in a more broad sense, forcing artists to give up their ownership on everything they make for a company.</description></item><item><title>Stop Following The Rules</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/stop-following-rules/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 May 2012 14:54:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/stop-following-rules/</guid><description>The fact that math, for most people, is about a set of rules, exemplifies how terrible our attempts at teaching it are. A disturbing amount of programming education is also spent hammering proper coding guidelines into students&amp;rsquo; heads. Describing someone as a cowboy programmer is often derisive, and wars between standards, rules and languages rage like everlasting fires. It is into these fires we throw the burnt-out husks that were once our imaginations.</description></item><item><title>The Standards Problem</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/standards-problem/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 May 2012 01:12:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/standards-problem/</guid><description>When people leave the software industry citing all the horrors of programming, it confuses me when they blame software development itself as the cause of the problems. Programming is very similar to architecture - both an art and a science. The comparison, however, falls apart when you complain about architecture and buildings having all these well-established best practices. The art of making buildings hasn't really changed all that much in the past 50 years.</description></item><item><title>An evidence-based refutation of the Project Glass parodies</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/an-evidence-based-refutation-of-the-project-glass-parodies/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Apr 2012 23:40:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/an-evidence-based-refutation-of-the-project-glass-parodies/</guid><description>It seems like half of the internet is complaining about Google's new wearable computers. They say that they're distracting, they say that you can't see through them, and they ask why you would want to be hooked into the internet like that in the first place. However, all of the basic usability complaints are built on critically unsound foundations: none of the complainers have used one of the devices. I've at least tried the technology1, and I have some facts and some ten-second experiments that I hope will address the more common concerns.</description></item><item><title>Language Wars Are Pointless</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/language-wars-are-pointless/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2012 17:48:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/language-wars-are-pointless/</guid><description>Sometimes it really amazes me when anyone actually takes language wars seriously. If I casually mention &amp;ldquo;pointless language wars&amp;rdquo; and someone leaves a comment ignoring my entire blog post, informing me that language wars are not pointless, I seriously question their priorities (and possibly their sanity).
Oh, was I not clear enough before? Language wars are pointless. They are pointless for 2 reasons: You are never actually arguing about the language, only design philosophies, and these language wars invariably disregard context, which makes all results of said war completely meaningless.</description></item><item><title>Why Windows 8 Does The Right Thing The Wrong Way</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/why-windows-8-does-right-thing-wrong/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2012 14:28:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/why-windows-8-does-right-thing-wrong/</guid><description>Yesterday, I saw a superb presentation called &amp;ldquo;When The Consoles Die, What Comes Next?&amp;rdquo; by Ben Cousins. It demonstrates that mobile gaming is behaving as a disruptive technology, and is causing the same market decline in consoles that consoles themselves did to arcades in the 1990s. He also demonstrates how TV crushed cinema in a similar manner - we just don't think of it like that because we don't remember back when almost 60% of the population was going to the movie theaters on a weekly basis.</description></item><item><title>Well That Was Interesting</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/well-that-was-interesting/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2012 16:43:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/well-that-was-interesting/</guid><description>So today I go to an orthodontist appointment at 11:30 AM, and its bright and sunny out, but fairly breezy. Several hours later I leave for a final exam for CSE 373 at the UW. Still nice and sunny out, but also still very breezy. We start the exam, and 40 minutes in, the power cuts out and we're put into pitch blackness. A few seconds later, I can hear a generator hum to life and the power is suddenly back on.</description></item><item><title>Visual Studio Broke My Computer</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/visual-studio-broke-my-computer/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Mar 2012 16:22:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/visual-studio-broke-my-computer/</guid><description>So I'd been using the developer preview of VS11 and liked some of its improvements. When the desaturated VS11 beta came out, I hated the color scheme but decided I still wanted the upgraded components, so I went to install VS11 beta. Unfortunately the beta only lets you change its install location if the preview developer preview isn't installed, and the developer preview had installed itself into C:\ without ever letting me change the path, which was annoying.</description></item><item><title>Hiring the Wrong People</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/hiring-wrong-people/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Feb 2012 17:21:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/hiring-wrong-people/</guid><description>Several years ago, this famous rant by Bill Gates (here's a more readable version) made its way around the internet. What was remarkable about it was that Bill Gates himself flaming his underlings for many of the things everyone else was complaining about did almost nothing to improve Windows. What improvements were eventually made are usually attributed to many outside influences, especially Apple and the rise of tablet PCs.
This really isn't that remarkable to anyone inside the software industry.</description></item><item><title>Chill Out</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/chill-out/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2012 14:31:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/chill-out/</guid><description>I do not usually involve myself with politics and bureaucracies, but they have a way of creeping into every facet of human experience in an almost parasitic manner. Even in my own profession of software engineering I have to deal with pointless language wars, followed by people being pissed off that I called them pointless. Well then, let me be perfectly clear here: Language wars are pointless. You know what else is pointless?</description></item><item><title>Implicit UI Design</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/implicit-ui-design/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2012 10:18:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/implicit-ui-design/</guid><description>For a long time, I have been frustrated with the poor UI design that is rampant in the software industry. As a consequence, many Linux enthusiasts have pointed out how productive you can be with Emacs, VIM, and other keyboard-shortcut/terminal oriented software. The UI design has gotten so bad, I have to agree that in comparison to recent user interface designs, keyboard shortcuts are looking rather appealing. This, however, doesn't mean that one approach is inherently better than another, simply that modern user interfaces suck.</description></item><item><title>Linux Mint 12 KDE</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/linux-mint-12-kde/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Feb 2012 10:32:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/linux-mint-12-kde/</guid><description>Over the course of 3 hours spent trying to figure out why my Linux Mint 12 KDE installation would to go to a permanent black screen on boot, I managed to overheat part of my computer (at least that is the only thing that could explain this) to the point where it'd lock up on the POST and had to give up until this morning, where I managed to figure out that I could delete the xorg.</description></item><item><title>'Programmer' is an Overgeneralization</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/new-post/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2012 20:59:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/new-post/</guid><description>Earlier today, I came across a post during a google-fu session that claimed that no one should use the C++ standard library function make_heap, because almost nobody uses it correctly. I immediately started mentally ranting about how utterly ridiculous this claim is, because anyone whose gone to a basic algorithm class would know how to properly use make_heap. Then I started thinking about all the programmers who don't know what a heap is, and furthermore probably don't even need to know.</description></item><item><title>Wikipedia's Identity Crisis</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/wikipedias-identity-crisis/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2012 01:31:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/wikipedias-identity-crisis/</guid><description>I assume we've all heard the term &amp;ldquo;deletionism&amp;quot;, but for the uninitiated, it simply describes a point of view that Wikipedia should only consist of high quality articles that would be relevant to an encyclopedia. This is in stark contrast to inclusionism, which contends that anything remotely useful should be retained. These two factions have been at war for quite some time, flaring up when any particularly contentious deletion debate arises.</description></item><item><title>Your Esoteric Language is Useless</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/your-esoteric-language-is-useless/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Dec 2011 17:55:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/your-esoteric-language-is-useless/</guid><description>You'd think that programmers would get over these ridiculous language wars. The consensus should be that any one programmer is going to use whatever language they are most comfortable with that gets the job done most efficiently. If someone knows C/C++, C#, and Java, they're probably going to use C++ to write a console game. You can argue that language [x] is terrible because of [x], but the problem is that ALL languages are terrible for one reason or another.</description></item><item><title>The Great Mystery of Linear Gradient Lighting</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/great-mystery-of-linear-gradient/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 13:36:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/great-mystery-of-linear-gradient/</guid><description>A long, long time ago, in pretty much the same place I'm sitting in right now, I was learning how one would do 2D lighting with soft shadows and discovered the age old adage in 2D graphics: linear gradient lighting looks better than mathematically correct inverse square lighting.
Strange.
I brushed it off as artistic license and perceptual trickery, but over the years, as I dug into advanced lighting concepts, nothing could explain this.</description></item><item><title>Signed Integers Considered Stupid (Like This Title)</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/signed-integers-considered-stupid-like/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Nov 2011 16:02:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/signed-integers-considered-stupid-like/</guid><description>Unrelated note: If you title your article &amp;ldquo;[x] considered harmful&amp;rdquo;, you are a horrible person with no originality. Stop doing it.
Signed integers have always bugged me. I've seen quite a bit of signed integer overuse in C#, but it is most egregious when dealing with C/C++ libraries that, for some reason, insist on using for(int i = 0; i &amp;lt; 5; ++i). Why would you ever write that? i cannot possibly be negative and for that matter shouldn't be negative, ever.</description></item><item><title>Why Kids Hate Math</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/why-kids-hate-math/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2011 03:44:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/why-kids-hate-math/</guid><description>They're teaching it wrong.
And I don't just mean teaching the concepts incorrectly (although they do plenty of that), I mean their teaching priorities are completely backwards. Set Theory is really fun. Basic Set Theory can be taught to someone without them needing to know how to add or subtract. We teach kids Venn Diagrams but never teach them all the fun operators that go with them? Why not? You say they won't understand?</description></item><item><title>Don't Work on Someone Else's Dream</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/importance-of-importance/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2011 23:25:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/importance-of-importance/</guid><description>When I complain to my friends about a recent spat of not being productive, they often remind me of the occasional 10 hours I spend forgetting to eat while hunting down a bug. When introducing myself, I am always clear that, most of the time, I am either busy, or trying to be busy. Everything to me is work, everything that makes me proud of myself is work, everything in my future will, hopefully, be more work.</description></item><item><title>C# to C++ Tutorial - Part 3: Classes and Structs and Inheritance (OH MY!)</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/c-to-c-tutorial-part-3-classes-and/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2011 18:07:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/c-to-c-tutorial-part-3-classes-and/</guid><description>[ 1 · 2 · 3 · 4 &amp;middot; 5 &amp;middot; 6 &amp;middot; 7 ]
Classes in C#, like most object-oriented languages, are very similar to their C++ counterparts. They are declared with class, exist between brackets and inherit classes using a colon &amp;#39;:&amp;#39;. Note, however, that all classes in C++ must end with a semicolon! You will forget this semicolon, and then all the things will break. You can do pretty much everything you can do with a C# class in a C++ class, except that C++ does not have partial classes, and in C++ classes themselves cannot be declared public, protected or private.</description></item><item><title>The Problem of Vsync</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/problem-of-vsync/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2011 04:43:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/problem-of-vsync/</guid><description>If you were to write directly to the screen when drawing a bouncing circle, you would run into some problems. Because you don't do any buffering, your user might end up with a quarter circle drawn for a frame. This can be solved through Double Buffering, which means you draw the circle on to a backbuffer, then &amp;ldquo;flip&amp;rdquo; (or copy) the completed image on to the screen. This means you will only ever send a completely drawn scene to the monitor, but you will still have tearing issues.</description></item><item><title>Musical Genres</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/musical-genres/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 16:29:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/musical-genres/</guid><description>As a composer, I have been on the receiving end of a lot of musical criticism - some useful, most ridiculous. I have given out quite a bit of criticism myself, but after discovering that most people aren't interested in brutally honest opinions, I have since avoided it. However, one thing that continues to come up over and over again is someone complaining about Genres.
&amp;ldquo;This is too fast to be trance.</description></item><item><title>C# to C++ Tutorial - Part 2: Pointers Everywhere!</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/c-to-c-tutorial-part-2-pointers/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2011 19:35:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/c-to-c-tutorial-part-2-pointers/</guid><description>[ 1 · 2 · 3 · 4 · 5 · 6 · 7]
We still have a lot of ground to cover on pointers, but before we do, we need to address certain conceptual frameworks missing from C# that one must be intimately familiar with when moving to C++.
Specifically, in C# you mostly work with the Heap. The heap is not difficult to understand - its a giant lump of memory that you take chunks out of to allocate space for your classes.</description></item><item><title>Radians: An explanation</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/radians-explanation/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2011 17:22:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/radians-explanation/</guid><description>Radians are used in almost everything that involves computers, and often come up in mathematical equations. However, most people are used to measuring angles in degrees, even though degrees (unlike radians) are a completely arbitrary measurement. To understand Radians, you need to understand $$ \pi $$, or more precisely, why it sucks. Like a black hole, except black holes don't actually suck, they just warp space-time so you fall into themOK BACK ON TOPIC:</description></item><item><title>C# to C++ Tutorial - Part 1: Basics of Syntax</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/c-to-c-tutorial-part-1-basics-of-syntax/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2011 04:26:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/c-to-c-tutorial-part-1-basics-of-syntax/</guid><description>[ 1 · 2 · 3 · 4 · 5 · 6 · 7]
When moving from C# to C++, one must have a very deep knowledge of what C# is actually doing when you run your program. Doing so allows you to recognize the close parallels between both languages, and why and how they are different. This tutorial will assume you have a fairly strong grasp of C#, but may not be familiar with some of its more arcane attributes.</description></item><item><title>On Hacking (or Why We Need Security Ratings)</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/on-hackers/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Jun 2011 17:56:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/on-hackers/</guid><description>Another website has been hacked. It seems almost routine now, with site after site getting demolished by hackers. The overwhelming public response to the catastrophe has been to ask, &amp;ldquo;can anything be made secure?&amp;rdquo; Security experts, naturally, are constantly attacking the companies in question for their dismal security practices, but what of the general public? They don't know what a hash is. They don't know what an SQL injection is. They have no reason to know these things and will never understand them.</description></item><item><title>My Mom Had a Heart Attack</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/my-mom-had-heart-attack/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2011 01:09:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/my-mom-had-heart-attack/</guid><description>She is fine and will make a full recovery.
About 3 weeks ago, on Thursday, May 19th, at approximately 6 PM, my mom went into ventricular fibrillation and collapsed while walking on a nearby trail. She was found by two walkers who called 911 and initiated CPR. After almost a half hour of CPR and 3 defibrillator attempts, she was stabilized and taken to the nearby hospital. She had no identification, so we didn't know about it until after 2 hours of failed searching, at which point my dad called the local hospital.</description></item><item><title>The Religion Problem: Perspectives</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/religion-problem-perspectives/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2011 06:06:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/religion-problem-perspectives/</guid><description>I view religion as a symptom of humanity's inability to operate as a rational agent. This statement will usually validate itself by being misinterpreted as an attack on religion, despite the statement itself simply stating that religion is irrational, not that it is a bad thing. Furthermore, we don't know if irrationality is inherently bad or worse than rationality, although humanity in general seems to prefer thinking of itself as rational despite repeatedly acting in completely irrational ways, usually without knowing it.</description></item><item><title>The Ninth Circle of Bugs</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/ninth-circle-of-bugs/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2011 04:43:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/ninth-circle-of-bugs/</guid><description>So I'm rewriting my 2D culling kd-tree for my graphics engine, and a strange bug pops up. On release mode, one of the images vanished. Since it didn't happen in debug mode, it was already a heisenbug. A heisenbug is defined as a bug that vanishes when you try to find it. It took me almost a day to trace the bug to the rebalance function. At first I thought the image had simply been removed from a node accidentally, but this wasn't the case.</description></item><item><title>Save RSS</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/save-rss/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 May 2011 22:03:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/save-rss/</guid><description>A recent article by Jesse Stay describes how Twitter and Facebook are killing RSS. Many people point out that you don't really need an RSS feed for either service, since the content they generate is not particularly conducive to an RSS feed. While this is strictly true if you are attempting to read the actual RSS feed, I don't consider this the primary benefit of an RSS feed.
RSS feeds provide a way to broadcast data in a standard format, which then allows an application to be quickly constructed using an RSS parser to process that data.</description></item><item><title>College Is Broken</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/college-is-broken/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2011 21:08:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/college-is-broken/</guid><description>The reason I have been repeatedly rejected from the computer science major at my college is partly due to underfunded and crowded conditions, but primarily because they are letting in the wrong students. Apparently, had I gotten a 3.5 in all of my classes, I would have been in the major already. Because I instead got a 4.0 in one class and a 3.0 in another, they have rejected me. Why?</description></item><item><title>An Outside Perspective on the PSN Fiasco</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/outside-perspective-on-psn-fiasco/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2011 21:11:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/outside-perspective-on-psn-fiasco/</guid><description>I asked a non-technical friend of mine, who has been unable to play online with his PS3 recently due to the PSN outage, what he thought about practically all of his personal information being compromised due to an intrusion and questionable security. His perspective is not what I was expecting.
I have no idea what proper security is because I have no idea how that happens. I kinda cross my fingers that paypal isn't absolute shit.</description></item><item><title>Future Predictions</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/future-predictions/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2011 15:54:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/future-predictions/</guid><description>In the past I've made several predictions that were dismissed, at the time, as ludicrous, but have in fact come to fruition, like the importance of having dynamic environments in games and graphics engines that can handle it. So, here I present a complete list of all the computer-related or economic predictions I currently have, along with justification:
Speed becomes paramount to all mature markets: People have been ignoring speed for as long as they can, because its apparently rather difficult for programmers to properly optimize programs.</description></item><item><title>Investigating Low-level CPU Performance</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/investigating-low-level-cpu-performance/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2011 17:06:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/investigating-low-level-cpu-performance/</guid><description>While reconstructing my threaded Red-Black tree data structure, I naturally assumed that due to invalid branch predictions costing significant amounts of performance, by eliminating branching in low-level data structures, one can significant enhance the performance of your application. I did some profiling and was stunned to discover that my new, optimized Red Black tree was&amp;hellip; SLOWER then the old one! This can't be right, I eliminated several branches and streamlined the whole thing, how can it be SLOWER?</description></item><item><title>The Bullying Never Stops</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/bullying-never-stops/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2011 14:22:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/bullying-never-stops/</guid><description>I believe that at a young age, I was physically harassed a couple of times, but I have long since forgotten. What I haven't forgotten is the intellectual bullying I was subjected to during 7th grade. There is not a day that goes by that my actions are not subtly influenced by when I misprounced &amp;ldquo;subtle&amp;rdquo; as &amp;ldquo;sub&amp;rdquo;-&amp;ldquo;tle&amp;rdquo; and was made a laughingstock in front of my honors class, several of whom told me that I was a hopeless idiot who couldn't do anything right.</description></item><item><title>Aquaria Hints</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/aquaria-hints/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Dec 2010 22:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/aquaria-hints/</guid><description>I don't care how you get it, go play Aquaria. The only 2D game that's better then Aquaria is Braid, and yet very few people have played or even heard of it. It's quite simply one of the most incredible masterpieces in game design, music and art that I have ever seen. If you don't like all the exploring, then use a walkthrough, but somehow, just play the game and beat it, preferably finding the secret ending.</description></item><item><title>The IM Failure</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/im-failure/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Nov 2010 03:56:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/im-failure/</guid><description>This is completely insane. First, Microsoft has rendered its new Windows Live Messenger (previously MSN messenger) almost completely useless.
No more handwriting No more setting your name to anything other then your first and last name. All links you click on redirect you to a page from Microsoft warning you about the dangers of the internet, requiring you to click a link to proceed. All photosharing is now incompatible with previous versions of messenger, and instead of actually just sending the file, it will instead fail completely.</description></item><item><title>How To Train Your Dragon</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/how-to-train-your-dragon/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Oct 2010 04:42:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/how-to-train-your-dragon/</guid><description>&amp;hellip;takes its place as one of my favorite movies of all time. The characters are brilliant, the story is superb, the music is divine, and the cinematography is breathtaking. It was so good it gave me the last bit of inspiration I needed to make this (WIP), and as a result my attempts at finishing CEGUI this weekend were thrown out the window. Tomorrow I'll try a first draft of the drums and possible a couple of effects before extending the main chorus.</description></item><item><title>Album For Sale! [Renascent]</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/album-for-sale-renascent/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2010 01:21:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/album-for-sale-renascent/</guid><description>Due to Bandcamp's sudden threat to turn all of my free downloads into paid ones, I decided to go ahead and start selling my music properly. Renascent is now available for $3, or about as much as a gallon of milk costs. It contains remastered, super high quality (lossless if you choose to download in FLAC format) versions of all 14 songs, in addition to the original FLP project files used to create them.</description></item><item><title>WavSaver</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/wavsaver/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Aug 2010 19:37:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/wavsaver/</guid><description>There is a documented bug in windows 7 that has pissed me off a few times and recently crippled a friend of mine, where a .wav file with corrupted metadata causes explorer.exe to go into an infinite loop. My friend has a large collection of wavs that somehow got corrupted, so I wrote this program to strip them of all metadata. Due to the nature of the bug, the program can't delete them (you must use the command prompt to do that), but rather creates a folder called &amp;ldquo;safe&amp;rdquo; with all the stripped wav files inside of it.</description></item><item><title>Pixel Perfect Hit Testing</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/pixel-perfect-hit-testing/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2010 06:27:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/pixel-perfect-hit-testing/</guid><description>After beating World of Goo after stabilizing things in my game and renaming it, I wondered how easy it was to decompile C# applications and simultaneously thought this would be a great opportunity to get pixel perfect hit testing to work on my engine. So, I decompiled GearGOD's composition example and quickly discovered that his method of detecting mouse messages was&amp;hellip; well something completely different then his extremely bad attempt at explaining it to me had suggested.</description></item><item><title>Fractal Cycle Screensaver</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/fractal-cycle-screensaver/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Aug 2010 15:26:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/fractal-cycle-screensaver/</guid><description>Binaries
Source Code</description></item><item><title>8-bit color cycling</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/8-bit-color-cycling/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2010 07:58:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/8-bit-color-cycling/</guid><description>Someone linked me to this awesome webpage that uses HTML5 to do 8-bit palette color cycling using Mark Ferrari's technique and art. I immediately wanted to implement it in my graphics engine, but soon realized that the technique is so damn old that no modern graphics card supports it anymore. So, I have come up with a pixel shader that creates the same functionality, either by having one image with an alpha channel containing the palette indices and a separate texture acting as the palette, or you can combine them into a single image.</description></item><item><title>Physics Networking</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/physics-networking/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2010 04:18:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/physics-networking/</guid><description>I'm still working on integrating physics into my game, but at some point here I am going to hit on that one major hurdle: syncing one physics environment with another that could be halfway across the globe. There are a number of ways to do this; some of them are bad, and some of them are absolutely terrible.
If any of you have played Transformice, you will know what I mean by terrible.</description></item><item><title>Assembly CAS implementation</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/assembly-cas-implementation/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2010 12:08:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/assembly-cas-implementation/</guid><description>inline unsigned char BSS_FASTCALL asmcas(int *pval, int newval, int oldval) { unsigned char rval; __asm { #ifdef BSS_NO_FASTCALL //if we are using fastcall we don&amp;#39;t need these instructions mov EDX, newval mov ECX, pval #endif mov EAX, oldval lock cmpxchg [ECX], EDX sete rval // Note that sete sets a &amp;#39;byte&amp;#39; not the word } return rval; } This was an absolute bitch to get working in VC++, so maybe this will be useful to someone, somewhere, somehow.</description></item><item><title>Function Pointer Speed</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/function-pointer-speed/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2010 22:24:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/function-pointer-speed/</guid><description>So after a lot of misguided profiling where I ended up just testing the stupid CPU cache and its ability to fucking predict what my code is going to do, I have, for the most part, demonstrated the following:
if(!(rand()%2d)) footest.nothing(); else footest.nothing2(); is slightly faster then
(footest.*funcptr[rand()%2])(); where funcptr is an array of the possible function calls. I had suspected this after I looked at the assembly, and a basic function pointer call like that takes around 11 instructions whereas a normal function call takes a single instruction.</description></item><item><title>Most Bizarre Error Ever</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/most-bizarre-error-ever/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 May 2010 00:48:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/most-bizarre-error-ever/</guid><description>Ok probably not the most bizarre error ever but it's definitely the weirdest for me.
My graphics engine has a Debug, a Release, and a special Release STD version that's compatible with CLI function requirements and other dependencies. These are organized as 3 separate configurations in my solution for compiling. Pretty normal stuff.
My example applications are all set to be dependent on the graphics engine project, which means visual studio automatically compiles the proper lib file into the project.</description></item><item><title>Floating Point Preformance</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/floating-point-preformance/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2010 01:53:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/floating-point-preformance/</guid><description>Whenever I do intensive performance testing on delicate math operations, the results almost always surprise me. Today I have learned that if a program preforms a divide-by-zero on a floating point operation (which does not blow up the program), the resulting performance hit is almost equivalent to taking a square root.</description></item><item><title>Watch This Now</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/watch-this-now/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2010 23:49:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/watch-this-now/</guid><description>The following movie was made, in its entirety, by a single person. It is entirely CGI, and if you don't believe me, check out the compositing breakdown.
The Third &amp;amp; The Seventh from Alex Roman on Vimeo.</description></item><item><title>Physics-oriented Network Interpolation</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/physics-oriented-network-interpolation/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2009 11:04:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/physics-oriented-network-interpolation/</guid><description>Syncing a game over a client server connection is not an easy task. It's actually extraordinarily difficult and is almost completely reliant on the quality of interpolation. Due to the nature of interpolation, it gets exponentially more inaccurate the more time is spent doing it. Therefore, a game designer should want to minimize the amount needed. This is not an easy task, but it usually involves using the server as a middleman to halve the interpolation time.</description></item><item><title>Proving Strong AI</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/proving-strong-ai/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2009 23:57:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/proving-strong-ai/</guid><description>I stumped my philosophy professor today. We were discussing the Chinese Room Thought Experiment and how it proves that a Strong AI is impossible (a strong AI being a thinking machine). The experiment is based on the idea that someone is sitting in a room and Chinese symbols are handed to him. He uses a rulebook that tells him what characters to write in response to the symbols given to him, and he understands neither the input nor the output.</description></item><item><title>I now have an LJ</title><link>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/i-now-have-lj/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2009 19:07:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://erikmcclure.com/blog/i-now-have-lj/</guid><description>I'm not really sure why I made this, since the dA journal is perfectly fine, but journals on dA seem to work better for more artsy related stuff. On here I can spend pages and pages ranting about advanced programming concepts! Woo!
So, yesterday night I discovered that I am now #1 on the CTG Music Charts. This, in turn, has made it highly likely that I will soon be the most downloaded artist on CTG Music.</description></item></channel></rss>